Guide to the Juan Felipe Herrera Papers, ca. 1970-1998 M1043
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2: Manuscripts, Journals and Other Literary Material
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts, Drafts, and Notes
    - Tiatilicos. (two versions). 10/90. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Sun Glow to December's Diamonds -- I want to feel my mother's blessings & I have. Lietz field book, 11/6/90. 80 pp. (Saudi Journal) (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - 302. Draft for poem: "Saudi Journal" 11/10/90. with notes. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Muslin, Skin, Coal (draft 1) 11-24-90 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Shawl 11-24-90 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Uncertain Grace. 17 pp. 11/24/90. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Days of Invasion. 12 pp. 11/29/ 90. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Chicano/a Writing Culture in California 1964-1980: 1990 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Clay Spider - 1990 [Light green cover, 27 poems] (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Clay Spider - 1990 [Light gray cover, 30 poems] (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Days of Invasion - 1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Evasive Flickerings: A Review - 1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Hispa-trends: culture, change & loathing in the fast changing hispanic majority. A draft for poems Teatro comedy. 1990. 10 art sheets. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - The Hunger Tower: Canto XXXII - The IcéDiamond/ The Last Rings of the Inferno." Draft for poem. 1990. Iowa City.IA. 18 index cards. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Keeping Poems - 1990 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Klee Spider, poem draft, 3p. 1990. with edits. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - New Germanies - 1990 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Draft of "Normals, Zombies & Magicians." 1990. Fresno, Ca. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Saudi Journal - 1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Sin Chaketa. 5 pp. 1990. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Writing Notes -1990 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - 10. Article. "Tectonic Stitches: The Art of Rainiro Martinez." by JFH. With editorial comments by Victor Martinez. 1990. 3 pages. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - 3 Poems by Margarita Luna Robles - 1990 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Saudi Journal II. 12/17/90-1/14/91 (field book) poetry manuscript draft, notes. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Saudi Journal III (Lietz field book) 1/15/-1/16/91. Notes poems, dreams & Saudi entries. 80p. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Saudi Journal 1-25-91 (old version) (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Days of Invasion - 1-28-91 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Normals, Zombies & Magicians. 10 p. (3 versions). 4/14/91. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Tatarema. Poem. 6 pp. 5/16/91. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Blowfish: An Autobiography - 6-17-91 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Frida Metafisika: Shattered Beings - 6-21-91 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Notes on the Modern Art Museum Chicano Poetry reading (first time). Francisco X Alarcon. Alfred Arteaga, Lucha Corpi, Norma Alarcon. 8 handwritten pages. 7/11/91. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Blâk-Smith 12/11/91. 3x4. Artbook. 20 pp. Journal, notes. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Hispa-Trendz. 78 pp. 1991. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Pie Glasses - 1991 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Tell Frida I Love Her. 205 pp. (2 versions). 1/6/92. [unbound] [1] (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - tell frida i love her. 205 pp. (2 versions). 1/6/92. Spiral Bound. [plastc spiral removed] [2] (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - My Aunt Dolores Carries Jalapeños in her Briefcase. Draft for Children's poetry book. 22p. 4/27/92. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - My Aunt Dolores Carries a Jalapeno Briefcase. 21p. 5/5/92. Spiral Bound. [[plastic spiral removed] [1] (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - My Aunt Dolores Carries Jalapenos in her Briefcase 5-5-92 [2] (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Frida's Monkey /with letter 5-7-92 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - A Bowl of Beings 6-9-92 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Normals,... 8-4-92 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Normals, Zombies, and Magicians 8-24-92 [printout dated 8-4-92] (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - The Book of the Universe: Traveling at the Speed of Light -1992 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - White Sins - 1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - White Sins: Journals of Invasion. 1989:1992. 125p. w/ dust jacket for Guadalupe Review. Vol. 1. No. 1. San Antonio, Texas. 1992. Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center. Ray Gonzalez, editor. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Rejection Letters - 92 + 96 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Night Train to Tuxtla 1-26-93 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Dust Jackets for Night Train to Tuxtla (2) 1994, and Memorias from an Exile's Notebook of the Future. 1993. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 1st Draft for Calling the Doves/Children's Book. 4x6. 24 sheets, drawings. 3/10/93 (for Marlene [step-daughter's notebook]). (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - De Condor Con Alas. 6/22/93. 8x5. sketchpad. Notes. 20 pp. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Floating Cities, Coughing Radiators, phtocopy of book review by JFH, LA Weekly 11/5/93 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Fast Trax & Spirit Hours. 12/25/93. Poems, entries, travel notes & drawings. 100 p. (Keith Haring book). (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Roman Journals (love after the riots) 1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Draft for poem, "The Sea During Springtime." l993.3p. (with edits.) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Calling the Doves 2-13-94 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Velasquez Painting the Infanta Margarita (surrounded by the Lights and Shadows of her glory) 3-11-94 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Calling the Doves, children's book drafts. 30p. with preliminary sketches by Elly Simmons. March, July, 1994. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "South Alamo Street Runway" short act, draft. 1992. 7p. Loose sketches. lp. 5/8/94 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Masks. 8/5-6/94. Pencil, pastel drawings. 4x6. 24 pp. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Sketches and text for Calling the Doves (Children's Book Press), artist Elly Simmons. 10/94. 20p. [mostly photocopies of faxed material] (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Reviews of Calling the Doves. 1995-96. 17 pages xerox. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Other Chicana and Chicano Inventions. 3 pp. 11/30/94. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Book Proposal: Underground Missions. 12/19/94. 3 pages. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Latin Sarajevos. 133 pp. 1994. w/ Letter from publisher: Douglas Messerli. Sun & Moon Press, LA. 6/27/96) (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Noche Verde Nuclear 1994 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - "The Orientationationcafe: a Circus Performance" original unpubished manuscript, performed by the Manicrucirco at CSU-Humboldt, Arcata. Summer Arts Program. 1994. JFH. 16 pp. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - 5x8 Sketch book. 2/13/95. Poems, Scribbles, notes by M L Robles. 100 pp. (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Giraffe on Fire - 3-21-95 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Webbak Affabet. 116 pp. 4/15/95. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Poetry Galleys for American Poetry Review - 4/20/95 4 pp. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Broadway Indian. 16 pp. 5/95 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Wettbak Affabet. 87 pp. 9/2/95. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Sol entero fuego. Spiral pocket notebook. Notes, drawings. A draft for children's poetry book: Shirts for Goldfish. 11/2/95. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Draft for essay: How to Live with a Feminista and (still) be a Macho. 4p. 1995. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Pick-up. 23 pp. 1995. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Songs for Homeboys and Homegirls. 68 pp. 1995. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Cilantro (Drafts) Facials - 1995 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Studio Sketchbook. 1995. Notes & Sketches. 125 pp. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Jaguar Hotel - 1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Laughing Out Loud I Fly. (original first draft on Field Notebook: "Little Hunks" (1995) and Fold & Gathered sheets from Harper Collins, NY. (48 pp.) 1998. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Q -VO Riffs - 1995 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 187 Reasons Why Mexicans Can't Cross the Border 1995 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - 187 Reasons Why Mexicans Can't Cross the Border, published 1995 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Solesitos - 1-7-96 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Solesitos - 1-9-96 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Solesitos - 1-10-96 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - De sol se lamen los barrotes de la escuela - 1-10-96 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Little Suns - 1-30-96 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Broadway Indian 2-14-96 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Little Suns - Solecitos - 2/26/96 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Solecitos Ms. 2/27/96 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Cilantro Man - 3-96 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Shawaste 3-28-96 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Full Lotus, 3x5. Sketchpad. Notes, travel. 4/4/96. 90 pp. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - The Flying School - 5-3-96 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Giraffe on Fire. 65 pp. 5/3/96. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - I Paint Myself Purple and Like Toasted Tomales - 5-3-96 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Juan Sock Too Many 5-3-96 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - The Upside Down Boy 5-3-1996 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Broadway Indian - 5-10-96 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Letter from Mary Hussmann from Iowa Review, regarding poetry galleys / with galleys 2p./ 5/28/96 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Galleys for Fourteen Hills journal, San Francisco, 2p 1996 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Concept sketch for "Macho Salsa: Reflections of a Salsista at the End of the Millenium" by JFH 7/4/96 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Domingo Dolittle's Alfa-Wak 7-96 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Domingo Dolittle's Alfa-Whak 7-96 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Normals, Zombies, and Magicians July, 1996 [7/31/96] (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Normals, Zombies, and Magicians 8-1-96 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Alfawakies 8/2/96 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Campesino Rainbows 8-25-96 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Campesino Rainbows 2nd draft - 8-26-96 [1] (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Campesino Rainbows. 27 pp. (two versions). 8/26/96. [2] (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - la Yorona Llorona (The Untold Stories) #3 Draft 9-8-96 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Going and Going (Yendo yendo) 9-11-96 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Going & Going (Va y Va). 41 pp. 9/11/96. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - At Airport. Journal entry. Two loose sheets. notes.9/22/96 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Going and Going (va y Va) - 9-25-96 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Going and Going - 9-26-96 [1] (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Going and Going - 9-26-96 [2] (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Going and Going - 9-26-96 [3] (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - B.O.W. [Blood On The Wheel] 10-7-96 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - 257. Notes on Nueral Darwinism.. 12/6/96. Handwritten. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Reporting on a Leaf. 12/14/96. Reporters Notebook. 4/8. 50 pp. Comedy notes, performance ideas. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Essay draft: Underground Missions" with edits. 36 pages. 12/22/96. (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Notes. JFH. Bringing Out our Radical Selves. Art, Writing, Test, Contributions. 1996. 1 page. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Macho Salsa - 1996 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Songs for Homeboys and Homegirls 1996 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - "Stanky Stoney" poem with ink drawing. JFH. 1996. (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - 21 Gun Salute at the Beginning of the New Millenium 1996 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - La Yorona 1-9-97 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Laughing Out Loud, I Fly 4-28-97 [1] (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Laughing Out Loud I Fly. 48 pp. 4/28/97. [2] (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - We Are All Saying the Same Thing. 75 pp. 4/28/97. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - If You Get There Before I Do. (Crash Boom Love) (five versions: 5/97-6/97). +/- 125 pp. [1] (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - If You Get There Before I Do. (Crash Boom Love) (five versions: 5/97-6/97). +/- 125 pp. [2] (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Shirts for a Goldfish 6-4-97 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Cesar Garcia and the Great Wave - 6-27-97 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Sketch pad. 3x5. 100 p. Emerald Phoenix Rises. 8/3/97. Notes, Outlines for Young Adult Novel (Yorona Moondragon Series), Vampire Chiles. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Che Guevera Motorcycle 2000 9-3-97 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Don't Worry Baby; Stand Up Poems 9-15-97 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Manuscript draft: "I Paint Myself Purple and with Toasted Tamales." Childrens book. 1997. JFH. l9 pp. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Preliminary draft of dust jacket for Laughing Out Loud I Fly. Harper Collins. 1997 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - The (Other) Big Yorona Book. l7 pp. 1997. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - "Poetry Project" newsletter Dec/Jan 1997-98. My review of XCP Journal inside. 31 pages. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 304. Draft for Teatro Act: "Maximum Security University." 4 pp. 2/15/98. Typed. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Women of Maize. l37 pp. 3/18/98 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Notebook of a Chile Verde Smuggler - 3/19-22/98 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Notebook of a Chile Verde Smuggler 3-27-98 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "Azure dynasty" Automatic poem on newsprint. Spring 98. JFH. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Going and Going - 5-1-98 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Rainbow Walker 5-1-98 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Upside Down Boy (Draft) 5-1-98 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Notebooks of a Chile Verde Smuggler. 329 pp. 6/18/98 [1 of 2] (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks of a Chile Verde Smuggler. 329 pp. 6/18/98 [2 of 2] (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Songs for Homeboys and Homegirls. 157pp. 6/23/98 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Notebooks of a Chile Verde Smuggler. 330 pp. 6/30/98 [1 of 2] (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Notebooks of a Chile Verde Smuggler. 330 pp. 6/30/98 [2 of 2] (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Justin Chanda. Letter (7/2/98) Dead Materials (Galleys, Drafts of Laughing out Loud) 150 pages; various sizes. Art & Text [1 of 2] (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Justin Chanda. Letter (7/2/98) Dead Materials (Galleys, Drafts of Laughing out Loud) 150 pages; various sizes. Art & Text [2 of 2] (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Study for Monologue: " Letter from Sir Buffalo Brown" 9 p. Handwritten. 7/98. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Border Crosser with a Lamborghini Dream 8-6-98 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Juantoomanys - 1998 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Laughing Out Loud, I Fly - 1998 (Fold and gather sample) (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Gato's Patio 2/87 (draft for Gato's Journal, art by Spain Rodriguez); Barrio Poet Cartoon by JFH (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Zenjose. Original Paste-up. Scenarios. Chapbook. San Jose, Ca. Hot Colors Press. 10 flats, 2 sided. 1988. (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2: Mayan Drifter, Drafts, Manuscripts, and Notes
    - In Search of Our Mother Dove Girl: Indian Journeys into Mexico. (First full draft of complete text idea/ Broken Moon Press, Seatte, Wa.) 10/9/93. [pp 1-158] (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - In Search of Our Mother Dove Girl: Indian Journeys into Mexico. (First full draft of complete text idea/ Broken Moon Press, Seatte, Wa.) 10/9/93. [pp 159-349] (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - In Search of Our Mother Dove Girl: Indian Journeys into Mexico. (First full draft of complete text idea/ Broken Moon Press, Seatte, Wa.) 10/9/93. [pp. 350-446] (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - In Search of Our Mother Dove Girl: Indian Journeys into Mexico. (First full draft of complete text idea/ Broken Moon Press, Seatte, Wa.) 10/9/93. [pp. 447-570] (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - In Search of Our Mother Dove Girl: Indian Journeys into Mexico. (First full draft of complete text idea/ Broken Moon Press, Seatte, Wa.) 10/9/93. [pp. 571-694] (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Mayan Drifter draft: Title page and Table of Contents, 1/31/94 [4 pp] (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Mayan Drifter draft. 3/28/94. [pp 1-132] (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Mayan Drifter draft. 3/28/94. [pp 133-272] (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Letter from David Bartlett, Temple University Press regarding contract for Mayan Drifter, 11/2/94 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Two flyers for Mayan Drifter. Temple Univ. Press. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Mayan Drifter draft. spiral bound. 5/8/ 95. [pp 1-136; plastic spiral removed] (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Mayan Drifter draft. spiral bound. 5/8/ 95. [pp 137-271; plastic spiral removed] (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Mayan Drifter draft, spiral bound. 8/3/95: with evaluation and edits by professor George A. Collier [Stanford/ Anthropology]. envelope and letter - 8/9/95. [pp 1-174; plastic spiral removed] (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Mayan Drifter draft, spiral bound. 8/3/95. [pp 175- 305 plastic spiral removed] (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Mayan Drifter draft (JFH). 9/24/95. [pp 1-154] (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Mayan Drifter draft (JFH). 9/24/95. [pp 155-304] (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Letter from John Sullivan & Michelle Rae (directors of Theatre Degree Zero, Arizona [Tucson, Bisbee] who produced my poetry and plays. l3p. Re: Hotel Jaguar Performance. Fall 1995. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Anahuak Vortex (Mexico City, 1996). Section drafts (12/31/95 & 12/30/95) 9 pp each. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Draft cover for "Jaguar Hotel" manuscript (Mayan Drifter), 1995 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Mayan Drifter, spiral bound. 3/14/96 (1/21/96 on cover) [pp 1-156; plastic spiral removed]. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Mayan Drifter, spiral bound. 3/14/96 (1/21/96 on cover) [pp 157-309; plastic spiral removed]. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Jaguar Hotel Draft. 4/8/96. 114 pp. [section]. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Research Materials, Chiapas: a) 13 Days/ 13 Dias: The Zapatista Uprising in Chiapas. 4/10/96. SF Mime Troupe's Performance Chapbook. b) Chiapas: Part One -One Boy/One Village by Tony Valenzuela 14 pp. Part: One Observer/One Village p. 14-34. Chapbooks. 1996. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Letter from Copy Editor. 7/1/96. 1 p. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Note from Copy Editor Elizabeth Johns. 7/5/96. 1 p. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Copy Editor's Queries. 7/9/ 96. 4 pp. with JFH comments. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Copy Editor's Queries. 7/22/96. 3 pp. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Jaguar Hotel edits & questions. 7/23/96.lp. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Copy Editor's Queries. 7/25/96. l00 pp. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Copy Editor' s Queries. 7/26/96 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Elizabeth Johns. 7/31/96. 4p. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Changes for Jaguar Hotel Section/ edits with notes by JFH. 8/18/96 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - New Layouts for Jaguar Hotel. 10/13/96 pgs.221-296. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Mayan Drifter page design samples.40 pp. 1996. (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Research Paper: Peasant Agriculture. Collier, George A. 80p. notes by JFH. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Mayan Drifter Glossary Edits. 1996. 7p. JFH. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Final edits (Almost). 3p. 1996. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Mayan Drifter Draft from copy editor. [pp 1-168] (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Mayan Drifter Draft from copy editor. [pp169-340] (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Mayan Drifter. Final version with editor's notations. [pp 1-166] (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Mayan Drifter. Final version with editor's notations. [pp 167-350] (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Mayan Drifter author's disks [3] (revisions, queries, reponses). 1996. [5 - 3.5" diskettes, 2 labeled obsolete] (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Two reviews of Mayan Drifter: Washington Post, 7/10/97; San Francisco Chronicle Datebook, 1/4/98; two publishing announcements. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Dust Jacket for Mayan Drifter 1997 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3: Journals, Notebooks, Diaries, and Other Similar Material
    - Zensoledad. Sketch Book. 5x8 7/18/87. Poems for Zenjose book, notes. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Journal entries: "June Journals: 6/88." 11 pages. (Mexico, California). (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Dream Notation. AWP [Associated Writing Program, Old Dominion University] Tabloid. Notes on Paper.. 8/20/90. 1 p. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - The Book of Angels. 9/27/90. 36 pp. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Angelitos de Oro y Rosas. Notes. 8/6/91. 22 pp. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Universos. 11/91. Poems, notes, sketches & dream journals. 55 pp. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Geronimo Flying Spirit. 9/24/92. 80 pp. Poems, dreams, notes & travel notes 22 to Mexico, Chiapas. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Chicano Kongz. 1993. 60p. 3/21/93-5/15/93. 60p. Poems, drawings & notes. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Hyperaxiological Skies. 11/93. Manila Paper Notebook. 20 pp. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Chi Flow Body All. 2/14/95. Letters, poems, notes. 60 pp. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Border Notes. 2/17/95. Drawings & Notes. 40 pp. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Zenboxhasnosides. 5/2/96. 9x12. loop. Journals, poems, notes, drawings. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - On Top of the Hill Gazing at the Sea Vortex. 5/13/96. l00 pp. Drawings, Notes, poems. 9x12. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Con luz y Sol /Total Freedom. 2/24/97. 9 x 12 pad. Notes, poems, sketches. 100 sheets. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Ano Tigre Topaz. 2/4/98. 35p. Notes, poems, sketches. 9x12. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - [Spiral bound notebook with handwritten notes, 2/20/77(?)-5/31//80(?)] (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - [Spiral bound notebook with handwritten notes, University of Iowa, 1989(?)] (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - [Small spiral bound sketch book with handwritten notes, circa 1989, 1994(?)] (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - [Spiral bound note pad with handwritten notes, circa 1991] (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - [Spiral bound notebook with handwritten notes, La Mission, "92(?)] (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - [Spiral bound notebook with handwritten notes, circa 1992-1993] (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - [Spiral bound notebook with handwritten notes, circa 1993] (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - [Spiral bound notebook with handwritten notes, 12/25/95-6/14/96(?)] (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - [Artist's notebook with handwritten notes and some sketches, circa 1995-1996] (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - [Spiral bound drawing tablet with handwritten notes, circa 1997-1998] (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - [Spiral bound notebook with handwritten notes, circa 1998] (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - [Spiral bound appointments book with handwritten entries, 1981] (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - [Small bound appointments book with handwritten entries, 1986] (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - [Spiral bound engagement book with handwritten entries, 1986] (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - [Spiral bound engagement book with handwritten entries, 1987] (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - [Spiral bound engagement book with handwritten entries, 1988] (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - [Spiral bound engagement book with handwritten entries, 1989] (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - [Spiral bound appointments book with handwritten entries, 1989-1990, University of Iowa] (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - [Small bound address and telephone book with handwritten entries, (1990?) (pages separated from binding)] (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - CSU-Fresno Campus Planner. Notes. 1990-91. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Campus Planner. 1993-94. Notes & Appointments, 100 pp. CSU­Fresno. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - America Angelic: Journals, Dreams, Gatherings. 11x14 Sketch pad. 4/14/97. 17 pp. (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Teatro Flow & Free. 2/11/98. Notes & Poems. 15 p. 9x12. (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Kings w/o Language. 9x12. sketch pad. Notes & Poems. 100 pp. 6/28/96 (Box 64, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Educational Career and Teaching Materials
  - Subseries 1: Stanford Dissertation Materials
    - Secular Rituals & Street Waves. Notes on Verbal Performance, Chicano Literary Movement. Dissertation Proposals. 1981. l50 pp. (Written in Seattle, Wa. and San Francisco, Ca.) [put with Stanford dissertation material] (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Memo to Professor George A. Collier, 8/7/81 (Re: Bibliographic essay; bibliography included. 11 pp. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Dissertation Committee letter. Stanford. 4/18/83. (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - The conceptual keys of this research. l3 pp. Notes on yellow legal pad. Early 80's. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Central Question: Scattered Notes. 5 pp. early 80's. (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Letter to Dr. Harumi Befu, Chair. Dept. Anthro. (RE: Re-instatement). 2 pp. 10/8/84 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Ph. D. Dissertation notes on the Chicano and Latino Literary Movement in the Mission District of San Francisco. [1 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Ph. D. Dissertation notes on the Chicano and Latino Literary Movement in the Mission District of San Francisco. [2 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Ph. D. Dissertation notes on the Chicano and Latino Literary Movement in the Mission District of San Francisco. [3 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Ph. D. Dissertation notes on the Chicano and Latino Literary Movement in the Mission District of San Francisco. [4 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Dissertation Writing Schedule. Insert A. Early 80's. (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Dissertation writing schedule, 1 p.[1985?] (Box 36, Folder 16)